Get ready for a killer ride.
Death Race is a action, thriller, science fiction
film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson.
Terminal Island, New York: 2020.
Overcrowding in the US penal system has reached a breaking point.
Prisons have been turned over to a monolithic Weyland Corporation, which sees
jails full of thugs as an opportunity for televised sport.
Adrenalized inmates, a global audience hungry for violence and a spectacular, enclosed
arena come together to form the 'Death Race', the biggest, most brutal event.
Jensen Ames, played by Jason Statham.
Warden Hennessey, played by Joan Allen.
Coach, played by Ian McShane.
Machine Gun Joe Mason, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Elizabeth Case, played by Natalie Martinez.
Pachenko, played by Max Ryan.
Death Race is a 2008 dystopian science fiction action
thriller film written and directed by Paul W.
Anderson, who produced the film alongside Paula Wagner and Jeremy Bolt.
Produced by Relativity Media, Impact Pictures, and C/W Productions, it stars
Jason Statham, Tyrese Gibson, Ian McShane, and Joan Allen.
The film follows Jensen Ames, a factory worker framed for a murder he didn't commit, who is coerced into the Death
Race, a three-day racing competition at Terminal Island Penitentiary, in an attempt to win his freedom.
Though referred to as a remake of the 1975 film Death Race 2000 (which in turn is based on Ib Melchior's short story "The Racer") in
reviews and marketing materials, Anderson stated in the DVD commentary that he thought of the film as something of a prequel.
A Death Race remake had been in development since 2002, though production was delayed by disapproval of early screenplays, then placed in turnaround
following a dispute between Paramount Pictures and the producer duo Tom Cruise and Wagner (the latter of whom produced without Cruise in the film).
Death Race was acquired by Universal Pictures, and Anderson
re-joined the project to write and direct.
Filming began in Montreal in August 2007.
Death Race was released in the United States on August 22, 2008, and in
the United Kingdom on September 26, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a financial
disappointment, grossing $76 million on a budget of $45–65 million.
Three direct-to-video films were released in the years that followed: Death Race 2
(2010), Death Race 3: Inferno (2013) and Death Race: Beyond Anarchy (2018).
The film explores themes of prison, martial arts, car
race, dystopia, matter of life and death.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.